Sufyan Jami

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Profile

Passionate software developer who has a love for writing clean, concise and efficient code. Technologies I like working with are Svelte, React, C#, Java, JavaScript, Python, etc. My portfolio showcases projects I have worked on and my passion for computer science.

Employment History

Full-Stack Software Engineer, Entergrade Solutions, Remote

DECEMBER 2023 - PRESENT

- Designed and developed a back-end API application used by over a million users.
- Tested API endpoints thoroughly, including edge and corner cases.
- Built front-end dashboards with Svelte and TypeScript.
- Created a standardized app shell to speed up front-end development.
- Worked with Microsoft Teams and Microsoft Admin Center as part of the application.

ASP.NET Core Developer, Canadian Bar Association, Remote

JANUARY 2023 - DECEMBER 2023

- Worked with various teams weekly to understand feature requirements and implemented them using .NET Core, C#, MySQL and Kentico 13.
- Enhanced user-experience when adding features while keeping the integrity of the software.
- Thoroughly tested each feature in various scenarios to ensure the best user experience and accessibility.

Tier 2 Forms Programmer, PBS Systems Inc, Calgary

APRIL 2019 — JANUARY 2023

- $\bullet \ \ \mathsf{Managed} \ \mathsf{programming} \ \mathsf{for} \ \mathsf{new} \ \mathsf{dealership} \ \mathsf{setups}, \mathsf{created} \ \mathsf{tailored} \ \mathsf{solutions}.$
- Automated important parts of the process to boost team productivity.
- Guided junior programmers through training, code reviews, and provided documentation for learning.
- Created various process documents to help new hires and team members work more efficiently.

Website Developer, All-In-One Digital, Calgary

DECEMBER 2018 - APRIL 2019

- Designed and Developed 10+ custom websites from start to finish.
- Worked with stakeholders to meet their needs and provide solutions.
- Implemented Search Engine Optimization.

Education

Information Technology - Major in Software Development, Southern Alberta Institute of Technology (SAIT), Calgary

Details

Calgary

Canada

587-437-7834

sufijami9@gmail.com

Skills

Svelte

React

Java

C#

JavaScript

TypeScript

Python

SQL

HTML & CSS

Node.js

Web Development

Unit Testing

Debugging

Version Control/Git

APIs and Libraries

Problem Solving

Microsoft Office